Daniel Mejia

UX/UI Designer

hello@danielmejia.me

(614) 558-7109

danielmejia.me

Summary

I have over ten years of experience in design, including eight years specializing in transforming complex workflows into user-centered digital experiences by prioritizing usability and inclusivity. I aim to empower all users to confidently and efficiently perform data-intensive tasks.

Professional Experience

Senior UX/UI Designer | JPMorgan Chase, Columbus, OH

Dec 2017 - Aug 2024

- Facilitated design thinking exercises in FigJam for stakeholders and engineering teams to plan and strategize at the
 beginning of the development cycle and again during sprint planning, enhancing collaboration, optimizing internal
 workflows, and achieving alignment between teams on the product roadmap
- Collaborated closely with UX research throughout both generative and evaluative studies, creating visual artifacts to
 enhance presentation clarity, improve communication with stakeholders, facilitate the iterative incorporation of user
 feedback, and foster a more user-centered design practice
- By pioneering the practice of usability testing with Figma prototyping, I significantly enhanced our product's UX practices. This approach ensured that we designed the right features intuitively, improving the overall user experience experience.
- Incorporated data-driven design practices, such as surveys and analytics, to identify user needs, define information architecture, improve navigation, assess customer satisfaction, and reveal internal product opportunities.
- Collaborating with the original author, I created documentation in Figma that adhered to the Greenlines System for
 Accessible User Experience. This effort and mentoring other designers were crucial in ensuring our internal product
 interfaces were A11y-compliant. I also designed an accessible email template to inform users about new features with
 each release and encourage communication to receive feedback.

Designer | McGraw-Hill Education, Columbus, OH

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

- Created a style guide and developed reusable HTML and CSS components that simplified implementation and ensured
 consistency across print and digital platforms, optimized design workflows, and reduced complexity, allowing five junior
 designers to manage tasks that were previously assigned to one senior designer
- Developed an interactive prototype and facilitated user testing sessions with teachers to gather feedback on a new and innovative math product, leading to a product that aligns teachers' goals with national educational standards standards.
- I was part of a task force assembled by leadership to accelerate the redesign and clarify a product's value proposition.

 This enabled our sales team to engage with education boards nationwide effectively.

UX/UI Designer | DESIGNATION, Chicago, IL

Apr 2016 - Nov 2016

- As a UX/UI Designer at DESIGNATION, I provided strategic design consultations to two startups in Chicago. I provided research-based recommendations for short-, medium-, and long-term strategies to create user value.
- Conducted one-on-one interviews with users for generative and evaluative research, synthesized data through affinity
 mapping, created wireframes and high-fidelity prototypes and performed usability testing. Presented artifacts to
 stakeholders, including journey maps, task flows, SWOT analysis, style guides, and documented UI mockups.

Education

Graphic Design The Art Institute of Fort Lauderdale, Fort Lauderdale, FL	Oct 2011
Associate's Degree	
Art History Universidad de Puerto Rico, Rio Piedras, PR	Jun 2008
Bachelor's Degree	
Intelligence Analyst (96B) US Army, Fort Huachuca, AZ	Nov 2004
Specialized Training	
Certifications	
Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) for UX Design MIT	May 2024
UX/UI Design Bootcamp DESIGNATION	Nov 2016